# Matt Vasquez

dwarfmondo.com 214. 502. 6766 mattvasquez@gmail.com 3737 Bunting Ave. Fort Worth, TX 76107

## **Profile**

I'm a software developer living in Fort Worth, Texas. Most of my days are spent designing and crafting software and leading software development teams. I really enjoy what I do and am passionate about creating products that delight, and promoting a team-centric culture for the companies I serve. I specialize in enterprise software design and development. I enjoy solving problems with an elegant user experience and a development process that enables continuous delivery.

## Experience

FOUNDER, SCRUMMAGE, LLC; FORT WORTH, TX - 2008-PRESENT

After trying many Scrum management tools to utilize at Fellowship Tech/Active Network, I found that there wasn't a product on the market that met all of our needs as an agile development team. I began working on Scrummage in 2008 and continue to work on it today with an awesome team. We have served clients such as <a href="https://example.com.">The Verge</a>, <a href="https://example.com">SB Nation</a> and <a href="https://example.com">booking.com</a>.

My responsibilities include...

- Customer Support
- Hiring
- Software Development (Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Middleman, SASS/SCSS, Backbone.js, MySQL)
- UI/UX Design

#### MANAGER OF SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT, OGSYS; FORT WORTH, TX - 2013-PRESENT

I was brought onboard to provide technical leadership and mentoring to the development team creating the next generation product for the company. Responsibilities include user experience and visual design, implementing Scrum and agile practices, serving as Scrum Master, architect and writing code.

My responsibilities include...

- Scrum Master
- Hiring
- Architecture
- Software Development (C#, <u>ASP.NET</u> MVC, SASS/SCSS, Backbone.js, SQL Server)
- UI/UX Design

#### DIRECTOR OF DEVELOPMENT, CAUSEMETRIC; ROGERS, AR - 2011-2013

Managed the development of a social giving platform called Pure Charity. Implemented the Scrum methodology and was Scrum Master, hired and managed development team members, wrote code (full stack developer).

My responsibilities include...

- Scrum Master
- Managing a remote team
- Hiring
- Architecture
- Software Development (Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Middleman, SASS/SCSS, Backbone.js, PostgresSQL)
- UI/UX Design

#### **UX MANAGER, THE ACTIVE NETWORK; IRVING, TX – 2010-2011**

Through acquisition of Fellowship Technologies.

### USER EXPERIENCE ARCHITECT, FELLOWSHIP TECHNOLOGIES; IRVING, TX – 2004-2010

I came onboard during the first 6 months of the company as a full stack .Net developer but moved into a user experience role a year or so later. I was also a member of the leadership team. Responsibilities included product design (visual and user experience), managing the UX team, working with engineering teams, font-end development including (HTML/CSS/JavaScript), full stack development.

My responsibilities include...

- UI/UX Design
- Managed UX Team
- Hiring
- Front-end Architecture
- Member of the leadership team
- Employee of The Year, 2007

## Education

University of North Texas, Denton, TX – Bachelor of Science, Business Computer Information Systems

### Skills

Product Design (UI/UX), Full Stack Developer (Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Middleman, Sinatra, MySQL, Postgres, SQL Server, JavaScript, jQuery, Backbone, React, SASS/SCSS, CSS3, HTML5), Git.

Certified Scrum Master, 2013-Present, Scrum Alliance

# References

Jeff Hook, COO, ParishSoft- (214) 668-9807, jeffhook@mac.com

Mike Rush, CEO, CauseMetric- (479) 381-0311, mike.rush@purecharity.com

Justin Patterson, Sr. Developer, Healthcare Payment Solutions- (817) 307-6341, justinpatterson@gmail.com